Guide to the Brooklyn, N.Y., Department of Law, Corporation Counsel records 2013.015
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 4: Property Files, 1851-1918; 19.3 linear feet; in 8 manuscript boxes, 4 flat boxes, and 1 oversized shelf.
  - Sub-series 2: Outside Brooklyn, 1883-1915; 14.25 linear feet; 9.25 in 3 manuscript boxes, 3 flat boxes, and 1 oversized shelf.
    - Manhattan - 55 Spring St. - Trinity Church lease, 1899 (Box 230, Folder 16)
    - Newtown - William and Regina Kammann to William Bourcea, 1883 (Box 230, Folder 17)
    - Oyster Bay - Massapequa - Dio Dekremen lease, 1903 (Box 230, Folder 18)
    - Oyster Bay - Massapequa - Parcel 7 - Beckhorn to Smith, 1906 (Box 230, Folder 19)
    - Richmond - Castleton - Map of District No. 1, circa 1898 (Box 236, Folder -)
      See also Union Free School Number 3, Town of Castleton - Foreclosure, 1898
    - Richmond - Canal St. and Brook St. library site, 1905 (Box 230, Folder 20)
      Staten Island
    - Smithtown - Kings Park, 1895 (Box 230, Folder 21)
- Series 5: Laws, 1867-1898; 0.5 linear feet; in 1 manuscript box
  Folder titles are derived from the documents.
  The series primarily consists of various records related to laws, acts, resolutions, and other regulations enacted or proposed by or to the Common Council of the City of Brooklyn (after 1897, the City of New York). The files span the years 1869 to 1898. Subjects include sewers, street openings, water supply, railroads, and civil service. Of particular note is one file related to improvements in Brooklyn Heights (1895).
  - Act in relation to sewerage and drainage, 1867 (Box 231, Folder 1)
  - Act to authorize the extending of certain streets to the East River, 1867 (Box 231, Folder 2)
  - Act to Alter the Commissioners Map, 1869 (Box 231, Folder 3)
  - Act to ammend the charter of the City of Brooklyn, 1869 (Box 231, Folder 4)
  - Opening certain streets in the 8th and 22nd Wards, 1869 (Box 231, Folder 5)
    Gowanus and Park Slope
  - Incorporaters Bridge bill, circa 1870s (Box 231, Folder 6)
    List of names and addresses
  - Act regarding street improvement assessments, 1870 (Box 231, Folder 7)
  - Act to provide for the speedy construction of sewers, 1872 (Box 231, Folder 8)
    Northerly of Prospect Ave. and Hamilton Ave.
  - Resolutions for Parks Commissioners, 1883 (Box 231, Folder 9)
  - Act to provide for furnishing an increased supply of water for the city of Brooklyn, 1884 (Box 231, Folder 10)
  - Construction of sewers in theTwenty Sixth Ward and Adjoining Wards, circa 1884 (Box 231, Folder 11)
  - Retention and Discharge of Employees by Head of Department, 1884 (Box 231, Folder 12)
  - Reducing speed of trolley cars, circa 1890s (Box 231, Folder 13)
  - Memorandum for opinion related to Brooklyn water supply, circa 1890s (Box 231, Folder 14)
  - Fulton St. Dock Obstructions, circa 1890s (Box 231, Folder 15)
  - Repair, rate of speed, and removal of snow and ice, 1890 (Box 231, Folder 16)
  - Common Council and Mayor, 1891 (Box 231, Folder 17)
  - Department of Parks, 1891 (Box 231, Folder 18)
  - Town of Flatbush - Proposal for the Construction of Sewers, 1892 (Box 231, Folder 19)
  - Transportation of Public Officers, 1894 (Box 231, Folder 20)
  - 29th Ward and 31st Ward Fire Department leases, 1895 (Box 231, Folder 21)
  - Act in Relation to Electrical Conductors in the City of Brooklyn, 1895 (Box 231, Folder 22)
  - Act to amend the highway law, 1895 (Box 231, Folder 23)
  - Brooklyn Heights improvements, 1895 (Box 231, Folder 24)
  - Whale Creek Canal, circa 1895 (Box 231, Folder 25)
    Lying between Meserole Ave. and Greenpoint Ave.
  - Act in relation to the jurisdiction of the department of public parks in the city of New York over certain streets in said city, 1896 (Box 231, Folder 26)
  - Act to regulate hours and wages of mechanics, workingmen, and laborers, circa 1896 (Box 231, Folder 27)
  - Department of Fire, circa 1896 (Box 231, Folder 28)
    Title 13 Section 6 Laws of 1888
  - Raising of funds for the maintenance of New York and Brooklyn Bridge, circa 1896 (Box 231, Folder 29)
  - Act to regulate and improve the civil service in the State of New York, 1897 (Box 231, Folder 30)
  - Civil Service Acts, circa 1897 (Box 231, Folder 31)
  - Local Self-Government, circa 1897 (Box 231, Folder 32)
  - Board of Alderman regulation of railroad companies, 1898 (Box 231, Folder 33)
  - Contracts for purchase of land for water purposes, circa 1898 (Box 231, Folder 34)
  - Police Department roundsmen, circa 1898 (Box 231, Folder 35)
  - Police Justices, circa 1898 (Box 231, Folder 36)
  - Public Libraries, circa 1898 (Box 231, Folder 37)
- Series 6: Miscellaneous, 1843-1915; 3.8 linear feet; in 4 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box
  This series includes miscellaneous material that did not fit within the scope of the other series. The series is arranged alphabetically by folder title.
  The series comprises a wide variety of material including administrative files, legal notes on unidentified cases, publications, payrolls, and other items. The records span the years 1843 to 1915. Of particular note are files related to civil service employment, the Wallabout Market, city water supply, the sanitation of the Gowanus Canal and Newtown Creek, and an audit of the accounts of the City of Brooklyn.
  - 6th District Brooklyn cases, 1906 (Box 232, Folder 1)
  - Administrative, circa 1860s-1870s (Box 232, Folder 2)
  - Administrative, 1889-1891 (Box 232, Folder 3)
  - Administrative, circa 1890s (Box 232, Folder 4)
  - Administrative, 1896-1897 (Box 232, Folder 5)
  - Administrative, 1899 (Box 232, Folder 6)
  - Administrative, circa 1905 (Box 232, Folder 7)
  - Administrative, 1906 (Box 232, Folder 8)
  - Administrative, 1910 (Box 232, Folder 9)
  - Agreement between the Village of College Point and the Snow Steam Pump Company of Buffalo, N.Y., 1897-1898 (Box 232, Folder 10)
  - Appraisal of Building #174, circa 1890s (Box 232, Folder 11)
  - Assessment forms, circa 1880s (Box 232, Folder 12)
  - Assessments for local improvements, 1898 (Box 232, Folder 13)
  - Assessors and their terms of office, circa 1867 (Box 232, Folder 14)
  - Audit of accounts (1 of 2), 1905-1906 (Box 232, Folder 15)
    This file relates to audits of accounts from 1892-1895. The following claims were referenced in the files: Dionus Frankel, Charles Hart, Edward B. Lansing, George F. Miller, Peter J. Montague, James O'Connor, Patrick Ross. It includes numerous receipts for excise license fees and audits of expenditures for the joint celebration of the completion of the Soldiers' and Sailors' Monument and the Discovery of America.
  - Audit of accounts (2 of 2), 1905-1906 (Box 232, Folder 16)
  - Bills, 1880 (Box 232, Folder 17)
  - Bills, 1897-1898 (Box 232, Folder 18)
  - Board of Education, circa 1887 (Box 232, Folder 19)
  - Board of Supervisors Minutes, 1893-1895 (Box 232, Folder 20)
    Regarding insane asylums
  - Business Cards, circa 1890s (Box 232, Folder 21)
  - Campbell, Catharine - Certification of death, 1869 (Box 232, Folder 22)
  - Certain pretended arrears of taxes, circa 1890s (Box 232, Folder 23)
  - Charitable Institutions - Distribution and appropriation of excise money, 1890s (Box 232, Folder 24)
  - Check book, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 232, Folder 25)
  - Civil Service notes, circa 1871 (Box 232, Folder 26)
  - Civil Service notes, 1889 (Box 232, Folder 27)
  - Civil Service notes, circa 1895 (Box 232, Folder 28)
  - Civil Service notes, circa 1896 (Box 232, Folder 29)
  - Clippings, 1861 (Box 232, Folder 30)
  - Clippings, 1867 (Box 232, Folder 31)
  - Commissioner of Charities - Lunacy Examination Bills, 1877 (Box 232, Folder 32)
  - Commissioner of Estimate and Assessment appointment paperwork, 1899 (Box 232, Folder 33)
  - Commissioners meetings, circa 1890s (Box 232, Folder 34)
  - Commissioners meetings, 1895-1896 (Box 232, Folder 35)
  - Common Council Stated Session, 1876 October 30 (Box 232, Folder 36)
  - Common Council Stated Session, 1881 December 12 (Box 232, Folder 37)
  - Common Council Stated Session, 1896 December 1 (Box 232, Folder 38)
  - Common Council and Board of Supervisors joint session, 1895 August 5 (Box 232, Folder 39)
  - County Employees, 1893 (Box 232, Folder 40)
  - Crosstown Line running times, circa 1890s (Box 232, Folder 41)
  - Daily Calendar - Assistant Corporation Counsel, 1904 (Box 232, Folder 42)
  - Daily Calendar - Assistant Corporation Counsel, 1907 (Box 232, Folder 43)
  - Delinquent Corporations in the City of Brooklyn, 1897 (Box 233, Folder 1)
  - Department of Charities and Corrections balances, circa 1896 (Box 233, Folder 2)
  - Department of City Works, 1887 (Box 233, Folder 3)
  - Department of Health regulations, 1887 (Box 233, Folder 4)
  - Department of Health - Weekly report, 1899 (Box 233, Folder 5)
  - Draft Calendar July Term - Before the Assistant Vice Chancellor of the First Circuit, 1843 (Box 233, Folder 6)
  - Empty Envelopes, circa 1870s (Box 233, Folder 7)
  - Empty Envelopes, circa 1890s (Box 233, Folder 8)
  - Ephemera, 1862-1866 (Box 233, Folder 9)
    Includes handwritten prayer, life insurance policy, Catholic Library Society invitation, and other items.
  - Far Rockaway sewers, 1896-1898 (Box 233, Folder 10)
    Includes specifications and contract
  - Free Public Libraries, 1895 (Box 233, Folder 11)
    Bay Ridge and Fort Hamilton
  - Gowanus Canal - List of signers to the petition for the improvements in the sanitation of Gowanus Canal, 1895 (Box 233, Folder 12)
  - Institute of Arts and Sciences - McKim, Mead and White architects agreement, 1895 (Box 233, Folder 13)
    Now the Brooklyn Museum
  - Kings County Treasurer's Office, 1890 (Box 233, Folder 14)
  - Laws for the organization and government of the Democratic Party of Kings County, 1904 (Box 233, Folder 15)
  - Legal Notes, circa 1870s-1880s (Box 233, Folder 16)
  - Legal Notes, circa 1883 (Box 233, Folder 17)
  - Legal notes and clippings, 1886 (Box 233, Folder 18)
  - Legal Notes, 1890s (Box 233, Folder 19)
  - Legal Notes, circa 1890s-1900s (Box 233, Folder 20)
  - Legal Notes, 1892 (Box 233, Folder 21)
  - Legal Notes: Sewer claims, 1895 (Box 233, Folder 22)
  - Legal Notes, 1897 (Box 233, Folder 23)
    Associated Cycling Clubs of Long Island memorandum
  - Legal Notes, 1898 (Box 233, Folder 24)
  - Legal Notes, circa 1899 (Box 233, Folder 25)
  - Legal Notes, circa 1900s (Box 233, Folder 26)
  - Legal Notes: Intention of law, circa 1900s (Box 233, Folder 27)
  - Legal Notes, 1902 (Box 233, Folder 28)
  - Legal Notes: Personal injuries, 1902 (Box 233, Folder 29)
  - Legal Notes, 1909 (Box 233, Folder 30)
  - Legal Notes, 1911 (Box 233, Folder 31)
  - Library Fund - Ira Whitman, 1863 (Box 233, Folder 32)
  - List of flooding claims, 1904 (Box 233, Folder 33)
  - List of licenses filed, circa 1890s (Box 233, Folder 34)
  - List of motormen, conductors, and plumbers, 1893 (Box 233, Folder 35)
  - List of names, occupations, and addresses, circa 1890s (Box 233, Folder 36)
    Possibly related to claim of John H. Keppel?
  - List of tasks completed, circa 1890s (Box 233, Folder 37)
  - Mail receipts, 1896 (Box 233, Folder 38)
  - McHugh, Neil M. - Property costs, circa 1865 (Box 233, Folder 39)
  - Memorandum to Judges, circa 1890s (Box 233, Folder 40)
  - Nassau National Bank of Brooklyn checks, 1902 (Box 233, Folder 41)
    Signed by Richard B. Greenwood (Assistant Corporation Counsel)
  - Nassau National Bank of Brooklyn checks, 1907 (Box 233, Folder 42)
  - New York and New York City civil service regulations, 1896 (Box 234, Folder 1)
  - New York State Service, 1894 (Box 234, Folder 2)
  - New York Supplement and State Reporter, 1897 June 3 (Box 234, Folder 3)
  - Newtown Creek sanitation, circa 1890s (Box 234, Folder 4)
  - The Old South Historical Work booklet, 1887 (Box 234, Folder 5)
  - Payroll for Street Repairs, 1861 (Box 234, Folder 6)
  - Photographs of shacks in a coastal region, 1915 (Box 234, Folder 7)
    Possibly related to water supply
  - Plans - Wall (?), circa 1890 (Box 234, Folder 8)
  - Police force rules, circa 1890s (Box 234, Folder 9)
  - Political speeches, pamphlets, and clippings, 1896 (Box 234, Folder 10)
  - Prospect Engine House Payrolls, 1887-1893 (Box 234, Folder 11)
  - Public Baths, 1879 (Box 234, Folder 12)
  - Public Markets and Restaurants, circa 1890s (Box 234, Folder 13)
  - Record of street reports, 1892 (Box 234, Folder 14)
  - Reports of Work and Time - Sewer Inspectors, 1861 (Box 234, Folder 15)
  - Rules and Orders of the Board of Supervisors of the County of Kings, 1895 (Box 234, Folder 16)
  - Salary for "Labor inspecting for leaky plumbing", 1897 (Box 234, Folder 17)
  - Schematic, 1905 (Box 236, Folder -)
    Used as exhibit in unidentified 1905 trial
  - Sealers of Weights and Measures, circa 1890s (Box 234, Folder 18)
  - Settled cases, 1895-1896 (Box 234, Folder 19)
  - Specifications for alterations and additions to Public School 105, 1900 (Box 235, Folder 1)
    59th St. and Fort Hamilton Ave.
  - Street cleaning bill, 1897 (Box 235, Folder 2)
  - Street cleaning contract notes, 1896 (Box 235, Folder 3)
  - Street opening expenses, circa 1869 (Box 235, Folder 4)
  - Tax bill fragment, 1873 (Box 235, Folder 5)
  - Unidentified, circa 1890s (Box 235, Folder 6)
  - Wallabout Market, 1884 (Box 235, Folder 7)
  - Wallabout Market: James Carroll and James Welin permit, 1886 (Box 235, Folder 8)
    Related to an unidentified 1890s matter (File no. 17)
  - Wallabout Market: Cold storage plant report, 1898 (Box 235, Folder 9)
    Report of Local Board, 4th Senatorial District, Borough of Brooklyn
  - Wallabout Market: Payroll, 1899 (Box 235, Folder 10)
  - Water rates complaint, circa 1890 (Box 235, Folder 11)
  - Water Supply, circa 1900 (Box 235, Folder 12)
  - Water Supply: Gravesend water use, circa 1900 (Box 235, Folder 13)
  - Water Supply: Valuation of buildings at the pumping stations, circa 1900 (Box 235, Folder 14)